

Ali Khalouf

☑ itskhaloufali@gmail.com 🤰 +971 55 388 5916 👂 Dubai United Arab Emirates

Profile

Senior Front-end developer & Open source enthusiast with over 6 years of expertise. With extensive experience in REACT, VUEJS, NEXTJS, Remix, SASS, WEBGL and API integrations. Self-taught in the areas of management and languages. A strong team player that effectively maintains professional relationships with co-workers, supervisors, and clients. Keen to learn.

Employment

Technical Team Lead & Senior Frontend Developer

Apr 2023 - Dec 2023

Artfi, Dubai

Technical Team Lead:

- Led the technical aspects of projects and supervised the development team.
- Gathered requirements and coordinated with stakeholders.
- Provided guidance, resolved technical challenges, and ensured project success.
- Mentored team members and fostered a collaborative work environment.

Senior Frontend Developer:

- Developed user-friendly frontend components using React, Next. js, NuxtJS, Tailwind, SASS, Shaden and TypeScript.
- Integrated blockchain using Thirdweb/Wagmi.
- Collaborated with designers, backend developers, and stakeholders.
- Conducted testing and debugging to ensure functionality.
- Provided technical guidance and reviewed code contributions.

Front-end Developer

Jun 2022 - Mar 2023

StarEx, Dubai,UAE

- Develop new features for the Blockchain website dashboard and StarEx Wallet using VueJS, Ether.js, and Web3.js.
- Implement new user-facing features for both users and customer support.
- Ensure real-time functionality in the chat system.
- Implement real-time chat functionality, enhancing the user experience.
- Build a Sponsorship Platform with an integrated dashboard.
- Develop the StarEx Academy Platform, providing a seamless learning experience.

Front-End Developer

Jan 2021 - Feb 2022

Personal details

Website

a-li.dev

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/khaloufali

Skills

VueJS

ReactJS

NuxtJS

NextJS

Websocket

SASS

Tailwind

Rest API

GSAP

WebGL

Team player

TypeScript/JavaScript

Remix

Open source

TypeScript

Languages

Arabic

English

Russian

Carbon Mobile, Berlin, Germany

- Implement new user-facing features in products that have a huge amount of PV every day.
- Write client-side code to create super-fast, easy-to-use, webbased applications which include websites for both desktop and mobile browsers, and hybrid in-app pages.
- Optimize web applications to maximize speed and scale.
- Contribute creativity and insight to solve both technical and business challenges.
- Research and promote new technologies and best practices within the team.

Chief Executive Officer (CEO)

Jun 2019 - Nov 2021

Sputnik Group, Moscow

- Led the development team that created the cloud base customer engagement platform screenplay.
- Architected and led the build of social networking and business platform
- Promote communication and cooperation among divisions to create a spirit of unity in the organization.

Front-end Developer

Mar 2019 - Jan 2020

Aqua Developments, Moscow

- Development of new features and improvements across all of the company projects
- Overseeing adherence to technical best practices
- Involvement in the entire software development lifecycle including technical analysis, architecture design, coding, code reviews, testing and release to production.
- Undertaking front-end development, based on React, Gulp, Vue and other technologies as needed.

Front-end Developer

Aug 2017 - Feb 2022

Upwork, Moscow

- Execute all visual design stages from concept to final hand-off to engineering
- Conceptualize original website design ideas that bring simplicity and user friendliness to complex roadblocks.
- Create wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps to communicate interaction and design ideas
- Demonstrate designs and key deliverables to peers and executive level stakeholders
- Establish and promote design guidelines, best practices, and standards

Web Developer

May 2014 - Jan 2018

Art of Touch, Tarous

Education

B.Sc. Information Technology

Sep 2019 - Present

Synergy University for Industry and Finance,, Moscow

Degree in Development, maintenance and security of information systems

B.Sc. Information Technology

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

Moscow State University of Technology STANKIN, Moscow

Development, maintenance and security of information systems

Spanish

Hobbies

- Listening to music
- Languages

VGO, Voronezh

Faculty of Russian language training for foreign students

B.Sc. Information Technology

Sep 2013 - Jan 2017

SVU Online, Tartous, Syria

Open source activities

Creator of Renix

Renix UI Component Library is a collection of reusable UI components designed for building modern web applications using React, Next.js, and Remix. The library provides a set of high-quality components that are customizable and easy to use, helping developers create responsive and visually appealing web applications quickly and efficiently.

Creator of araslug

"araslug" is an npm package that simplifies the process of converting Arabic text into user-friendly URLs. This package provides a convenient solution for transforming Arabic text, such as titles or article names, into URL-friendly representations.

Creator of Pigeon

<u>Pigeon</u> is a vuejs component library designed to help website owners easily add chat/live support and contact information to their websites.

Renux UI Component Nuxt Module

<u>Renux UI</u> provides a collection of customizable and reusable UI components for building web applications with Nuxt.is.